Guide to the Mulford Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Mulford family papers
1807-1967
1820-1900
MS 361
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7
(18 boxes, 1 folio)
Correspondence, diaries, sermons, essays, and other papers of Elisha Mulford, 1833-1885, Episcopal clergyman, teacher, writer, and political philosopher; and of other members of the Mulford and Jessup families.
Mulford family
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Subject File.
Biographical / Historical
The Mulford Family Papers consist primarily of the papers of Elisha Mulford, an Episcopal clergyman, teacher, and writer who was born in Montrose, Pennsylvania, November 19, 1833. Educated at Cortland Academy, Homer, New York, in 1852 Mulford entered the sophmore class at Yale, from which he graduated in 1855. He studied for the ministry at Union Seminary, New York City, and at Andover Seminary, Andover, Massachusetts. He continued his studies in Europe, at Berlin, Heidelberg, and Halle. Upon his return, Mulford was ordained deacon in the Episcopal Church in 1861, and ordained a priest by Bishop Odenheimer, at South Orange, New Jersey in 1862. In that year he married Rachel Price Carmalt of Lakeside, Pennsylvania. After serving as rector in South Orange, he retired from the active ministry in 1864 (because of deafness) and moved to Lakeside, where he devoted himself to study and writing. In 1870 he published The Nation, and ten years later, The Republic of God. In 1880 he moved to Cambridge, Massachusetts, where he lectured on theology from 1881 to 1885 at the Episcopal Theological School. Mulford died at Cambridge, December 9, 1885, and was buried in Sleepy Hollow Cemetery, Concord, Massachusetts.
Mulford made his most notable contribution as a scholar and political philosopher. His major book, The Nation, in many ways a work unique in the history of American thought, reflected the philosophical influences of Hegel, Stah1, Trendlenburg, and Bluntschli and the social and theological thinking of the English theologian Frederick Denison Maurice. Mulford rejected those theories which regarded the form of the state as a historic accident. Examining the forms and purposes of the state in their historic development, he defined the nation as an organism, a personality which responded to the ethical ideals and practices of the people. This ethical idealism was supported by an immanent ontology, an emphasis he later made explicit in his theological work, The Republic of God. But Mulford, always under the influence of his New England Calvinist heritage, placed the primary obligation upon the individual whose responsibility it was to strive toward an ethical consciousness informed by Divine purpose. Indeed, upon such consciousness, thought Mulford, depended the very destiny of the Nation.
The Mulford Family Papers, especially the notebooks and correspondence of Elisha Mulford, and his lectures, delivered at Cambridge Theological School and the Columbia Law School, provide important information on the sources and the development of American political philosophy in the Gilded Age, as well as the course of Mulford's own intellectual development. The Papers are arranged into three series: CORRESPONDENCE, WRITINGS, AND SUBJECT FILE. CORRESPONDENCE is divided between "General Correspondence," containing the letters either written or received by Elisha Mulford, and "Family Correspondence," containing correspondence among the various members of the Mulford and Jessup families(except for Elisha Mulford). Nearly two-thirds of the entire series consists of letters written by Mulford himself. Of primary importance is the correspondence with Lyman Dennison Brewster (45 letters), Francis Bicknell Carpenter, the artist, (16 letters), George Leon Walker (6 letters), William Thomas Wilson (72 letters), and especially, Congregational clergyman and advocate of the "New Theology," Theodore Thornton Munger (98 letters). (For Mulford's letters to Munger, see the Theodore Thornton Munger Papers, Historical Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University). There is also extensive and important correspondence with Mulford's wife, Rachel Price (Carmalt), and brother, Silvanus S. Mulford, which sheds some light on his personality and character. Other correspondents of note include: William Torrey Harris, Horace E. Scudder, Andrew Dickson White, and Alexander Stevenson Twombly.
The "Writings" series consists of manuscript notes, essays, and lectures, primarily on political philosophy and theology, as well as a number of sermons and a few addresses. Of special interest are the notes taken by five students on Mulford's lectures, 1882-1885, and Mulford's own notes on the lectures of Professor Hitchcock and Francis Lieber. There are extensive notes by Mulford on books and articles he had read-mostly on political thought - including his own thoughts and ideas for future publications. Two manuscript drafts of a book (never published), The Life of Elisha Mulford, as told in his Letters (probably compiled by Mulford's wife and son), contain excerpts from letters to his friends and family, from 1851 to 1885. In addition, there is a draft of an introduction to the book, written by Rachel Price Mulford, and correspondence to her about its proposed publication. Most important in this series, are Mulford's lectures on theology, literature, philosophy, and political thought, including a series of 33 lectures on theology given at the Episcopal Theological School, Cambridge, Massachusetts and a series of 6 lectures on political science given at Columbia Law School, (1872-1873?).
The "Subject File" contains biographical materials, family photographs, personal finances, and various circulars and solicitations. Most important is the family geneology, and a letter to the "Ministers of the Gospel in England and France," probably written by Mulford.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, diaries, sermons, essays, and other papers of Elisha Mulford, 1833-1885, Episcopal clergyman, teacher, writer, and political philosopher; and of other members of the Mulford and Jessup families.
Families; Philosophy; Sermons; Clergy; Brewster, Lyman D. (Lyman Denison), 1832-1904; Carpenter, F. B. (Francis Bicknell), 1830-1900; Harris, William Torrey, 1835-1909; Mulford, Elisha, 1833-1885; Mulford, Rachel Price Carmalt; Mulford, Silvanus S.; Munger, Theodore Thornton, 1830-1910; Scudder, Horace Elisha, 1838-1902; Twombly, Alexander S. (Alexander Stevenson), 1832-1907; Walker, George Leon, 1830-1900; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918; Wilson, William Thomas, 1834-1890; Jessup family; Mulford family; Episcopal Church; Yale University -- Students
- Correspondence, 1807-(1860-1885) 1900; Series I; 1' 3" (3 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is divided into two sections: "General Correspondence" and "Family Correspondence." "General Correspondence," which contains the correspondence of Elisha Mulford, is divided into two sub-sections: the first, letters received by Mulford, is arranged alphabetically by the name of the writer of the letter; the second and larger section, containing letters written by Mulford, is arranged alphabetically by the name of the person to whom the letter was addressed. Letters within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  "Family Correspondence" consists of the letters of various members of the Mulford and Jessup families to other members of the families (except for Elisha Mulford), such as Mulford's wife, Rachel Price (Carmalt), his parents, Silvanus S. and Fanny Jessup Mulford, and their children, particularly, William Jessup and Fanny J. Connell, and Elisha Mulford's grandfather, Elisha Mulford (1748-1828). This section is also arranged alphabetically by the name of the person to whom the letter was addressed; correspondence within each folder is arranged chronologically.
  - General - to Elisha Mulford
    - Brewster, Lyman Dennison, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Harris, William Torrey, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Jessup, F. T., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mulford, E. H., [1881] (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Mulford, Rachel Price, 1860-1870, 1872-1885, undated (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
    - Mulford, Roland Jessup, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Munger, Theodore T., 1857-1873, 1876-1885 (Box 1, Folder 11-14)
    - Scudder, Horace Elisha, 1869, 1871, 1874, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Winlock, Sara C. (Mulford), undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - unidentified, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - General - from Elisha Mulford
    - Brewster, Lyman Dennison, 1865-1882 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Carmalt, Sara, 1865-1870 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Carpenter, Francis Bicknell, 1849-1853, 1866-1867 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Chelly, 1862, [1863], 1881 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Cruickshanks, James, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Foster, Sophia J., 1853 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Garfield, James A., Pres., 1880 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Gray, George Zabriskie, Dean, Episcopal Theological School, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Harris, William Torrey, 1868, 1870, 1871, 1873, 1875, 1879-1882, 1884-1884 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Johnson, Charles Frederick, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Mulford, Benjamin Huntting, 1854, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Mulford, Fanny Jessup, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Mulford, Mary, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Mulford, Rachel Price, 1858-1885, undated (Box 2, Folder 31-40)
    - Mulford, Roland Jessup, 1884-1885 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Mulford, Silvanus S., Jr., 1850, 1853-1854, 1857-1885, undated (Box 3, Folder 42-45)
    - Mulford, William J., undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Mulford, William S., 1867 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Nichols, Starr Hoyt, 1859, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Scudder, Horace Elisha, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Simons, L., (1873?) (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Thompson, R. E., 1882 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Twombly, Alexander Stevenson, 1881, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Uncle, 1876 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Walker, George Leon, 1858, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - White, Andrew Dickson, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Wilson, William Thomas, 1856, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Wilson, William Thomas, 1864-1885 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Winlock, Sara C. (Mulford), 1882-1884 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Yardley, Herbert Albert, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Unidentified, 1855, 1856, undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Family
    - Connell, Fanny (Mulford) (from: Rachel Price M.), 1885-1889, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Connell, Fanny & Charles, 1887-1889 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Foster-"child" (from: Parents) Abigail (Jessup) Foster, 1822 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Jessup - Family, 1814, 1816-1817, 1823, 1833, 1836, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Jessup, William, 1819-1820, 1822 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Mulford, Elisha, Sr. - Family (from: Silvanus S. Mulford), 1817, 1821 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Mulford, Elisha, 1798-1867 - brother of Silvanus S. Mulford, Sr., 1822 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Mulford, Fanny Amanda (from: Samuel Buell Mulford, 1852, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Mulford, Fanny (Jessup), 1818, 1821-1824, 1837-1838, 1840-1841, 1843-1845, 1848, 1864, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Mulford, Rachel Price, 1885, 1900, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Mulford, Silvanus S., Sr ., (from: Elisha Mulford, Sr .), 1807-1828 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Mulford, Silvanus S., Sr., 1833, 1836, 1837, 1838, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Mulford, Silvanus, Sr. - Family (from: Samuel Buell), 1849-1850 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Mulford, William Jessup (from: Samuel Buell M.), 1838 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Post, George (from: Harriett (Jessup) Post, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Wilson, William Thomas (from: Silvanus S. Mulford - re. Elisha Mulford), 1860 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Winlock, Sara (Mulford), 1882 (Box 3, Folder 77)
- WRITINGS, 1852-(1880's) 1905; Series II; 5' 2 1/2 (13 BOXES)
  The "Writings" series is divided into a number of sub-sections and arranged as follows:
  Addresses- alphabetically by title.
  Books- alphabetically by category.
  Diary- alphabetically by title.
  Essays- alphabetically by title or the subject of the essay.
  Lectures - alphabetically by category and by chapter number within a lecture series, i.e. Cambridge Lecture Series and Columbia Law School Lectures. "General Lectures" are arranged alphabetically by the title or subject of the lecture.
  Notes- alphabetically by subject or title.
  Sermons - arranged by order of Old and New Testament books from which the text of the sermon is taken. Each listing notes the text and date of the sermon.
  - Addresses
    - Opening of Normal School, Montrose, Penn., undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Twentieth Annual Festival of the Society of Susquehanna County, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Books
    - Life of Elisha Mulford as told in his letters
      - Correspondence to R. P. Mulford
        - Brewster, Lyman Dennison, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Dodd, Frank H., 1905 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Harris, William Torrey, 1894, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Houghton, Mifflin Co., 1898 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Munger, T. T., [1892] (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - Scudder, Horace E., 1888, 1893, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 8)
          General note
          (also letter from Scudder to Atlantic Monthly, 1890)
        - Twombly, Alexander S., 1898 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Drafts
      - Copy 1, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Copy 2, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Introduction, [Rachel Price Mulford] (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Diary
    - Life, Works and Published Adventures While a Fellow of North, Middle Yale College, 1852-1853 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Essays
    - Analysis of [Philosophy of Aristotle] (incomplete), undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "From the Portfolio of an Idea", undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "The Idea of a Calling", undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - "The Influence of Maurice", Christian Union, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "Maurice's Christian Union"
      General
      See: box 5, folder 26
    - Political Maxims, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "Peace", undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Plato (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Political, 1871 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Religious, chapters III and VI (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Review, Reminiscences of Lord Ronald Gower (Charles Sutherland), undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Secondary school, 1846-1850 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Sociology" "Maurice's Christian Union", 1884 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Student, written by Mulford while at Yale, 1852-1854 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Theological series, introduction, 1871 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Theological Series, 1, 2, 3, 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Theological series, 5, 6, 7, 8, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Theological series, 9, 11, 12, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Unidentified fragment [on the state and organization of civil service], (post 1870)? (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Wiclif, John, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Lectures
    - Cambridge Series, Introduction I, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Cambridge Series, Introduction II, January 1885 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Cambridge Series, Introduction III, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Cambridge Series, Psychological Argument IV, November 1882 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Cambridge Series, Ontological Argument V, November 1882 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Cambridge Series, Cosmological Argument VI, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Cambridge Series, Cosmological Argument No. 2 VII, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Cambridge Series, Theological Argument VIII, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Cambridge Series, Ethical Argument IX, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Cambridge Series, Sociological Argument X, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Cambridge Series, Being of God XI, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Cambridge Series, Knowledge of God XII, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Cambridge Series, Personality of God XIII, December 1882 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Cambridge Series, Attributes of God XIV, January 1883 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Cambridge Series, Trinity XV, March 1883 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Cambridge Series, Revelation XVI, February 1883 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Cambridge Series, Christ XVII, April 1883 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Cambridge Series, Evaluation XVIII, January 1884 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Cambridge Series, Atonement XIX, 1883-1884 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Cambridge Series, Inspiration XX, 1883-1884 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Cambridge Series, Life of the Spirit XXI, undated (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Cambridge Series, Personality XXII, December 1884 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Cambridge Series, Bible XXIII, undated (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Cambridge Series, Christianity XXIV, December 1884 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Cambridge Series, Freedom of the Will XXV, 1882-1883 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Cambridge Series, Origin of Man XXVI, 1882-1883 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Cambridge Series, Ethics XXVII, January 1883 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Cambridge Series, Science, Religion & Philosophy XXVIII, January 1883 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Cambridge Series, Materialism XXIX, 1882-1883 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - Cambridge Series, Evil and Sin XXX, 1882-1883 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Cambridge Series, Affection, Faith, & Life XXXII, 1882-1883 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Cambridge Series, Miracles XXXIII, December 1884 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Columbia Law School, Political Science Survey & Lecture II, undated (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Columbia Law School, The Substance of the State Lect. II & III, undated (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Columbia Law School, Political Science Lect. IV & V, undated (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - Columbia Law School, Political Science Lect. VI Notes on Municipal Law, undated (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - General, "The Accident of Birth" (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - General, Books Read with Class, Reviews, 1884 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - General, "Christianity - The Condition of the (Truth) Character" (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - General, Cosmological Argument, November 1882-December 1883 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - General, Discourses (Theological), 1883 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - General, "Joy of Duty (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - General, "The Law of Love" (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - General, "Municipal Law", 1867 (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - General, "Notes on the Republic", 1882-1883 (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - General, "The Object of a University", 1883, undated (Box 10, Folder 79-80)
    - General, Organon of Theology, undated (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - General, Revelation, undated (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - General, Shakespeare, 1883 (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - General, Theological, 1882-1883 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - General, Theology, March 29, May 3, 1882 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - Theological, Organon of Theology I, 1882 (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Theological, Certainty of Faith and Knowledge II, 1882 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - Theological, Distinction of Theology III-IV, 1882 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - Theological, Existence of God V-VI, 1882 (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - Theological, Revelation VII-VIII, 1882 (Box 12, Folder 90)
  - Notes
    - Agriculture, 1884 (Box 12, Folder 91)
    - (a) Attributes of God: (b) Knowledge of God, undated (Box 12, Folder 92)
    - Book Lists [Children's Books], 1850, 1857, 1876, 1879 (Box 12, Folder 93)
    - "Defense of the Indians" (Box 12, Folder 94)
    - Doctrines of Impotance, undated (Box 12, Folder 95)
    - Family, 1882 (Box 12, Folder 96)
    - Guild of Authors, undated (Box 12, Folder 97)
    - History of Political Science, undated (Box 12, Folder 98)
    - Human Institutions, 1883 (Box 12, Folder 99)
    - Knowledge of God
      See: box 12, folder 92
    - Lectures by Prof. Hitchcock (taken by E.M.), undated (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - Lectures by Francis Lieber (taken by E.M.), 1867 (Box 12, Folder 102)
    - Memorial volume, undated (Box 12, Folder 103)
    - Misc. fragments (Box 12, Folder 104)
    - Nature, 1883 (Box 13, Folder 105)
    - On Human Society, (1885)? (Box 13, Folder 106)
    - Outlines for lectures, 1872 (Box 13, Folder 107)
    - Passages from Greek and Latin authors, undated (Box 13, Folder 108)
    - People's Hand Book, 1883 (Box 13, Folder 109)
    - Philosophical, 1884 (Box 13, Folder 110)
    - Political thought and writings, undated (Box 13, Folder 111-115)
    - Questions Before Congress, undated (Box 13, Folder 116)
    - References for articles, undated (Box 13, Folder 117)
    - Review of articles and books, 1883 (Box 13, Folder 118)
    - Sermons, undated (Box 14, Folder 119-122)
    - Sermons of Henry Ward Beecher (notes by E.M.), undated (Box 14, Folder 123)
    - Society, 1882 (Box 14, Folder 124)
    - Student, on E. Mulford's lectures on theology (notes taken by James V. Chalmers), 1884 (Box 14, Folder 125)
    - Student, on E. Mulford's lectures on theology (notes taken by Charlton P. Mills), 1882 (Box 14, Folder 126)
    - Student, on E. Mulford's lectures on theology (notes taken by W. D. Roberts), (1885)? (Box 14, Folder 127)
    - Student, on E. Mulford's lectures on theology (note-taker unknown), undated (Box 14, Folder 128)
    - Student, on E. Mulford's lectures on theology-misc., (1885)? (Box 14, Folder 129)
    - Theological, 1884 (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - Travel, 1859-1860 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - Two Schools of theology, undated (Box 14, Folder 132)
  - Sermons
    - Exo. - 3.6, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 133)
    - Psalm 8.2, undated (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Psalm 15.1, undated (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Psalm 15.1-2, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Psalm 46.10 (2 copies), 1863 (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Psalm 47.7, undated (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Psalm 51.4, undated (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Psalm 57.4, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Psalm 68.6, undated (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - Psalm 95.2, undated (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - Psalm 112.7 (3 copies), 1861-1864 (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - Psalm 122.3-6, undated (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - Psalm 137.5, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - Proverbs 8.1,3,4,8.3-4, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 136)
    - Joel 2.25, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 137)
    - Joel 3.14, undated (Box 15, Folder 137)
    - Joel 111.14, 1863 (Box 15, Folder 137)
    - Matthew 4.1, undated (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Matthew 5.2, 1863 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Matthew 5.6 (2 copies), 1863 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Matthew 5.20, undated (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Matthew 6.26, undated (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Matthew 11.28 (3 copies), 1861 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - Matthew 13.37, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - Matthew 23.37, 1863 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - Matthew 28.19, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - Matthew 28.20, 1863 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - Luke 1.6, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - Luke 1.38, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - Luke 7.27, 1863 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - Luke 9.55, undated (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - Luke 13.24, 1871 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - Luke 13.34, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - Luke 22.61-62, undated (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - John 1.4, undated (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - John 6.14 (2 copies), 1861 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - John 8.12, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - John 8.25, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - John 12.25, undated (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - John 12.32, undated (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - John 15.15 (2 copies, 1869 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - John 20.28, undated (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - Romans 2.1, undated (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - Romans 5.1, undated (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - Romans 5.4, 1891 (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - Romans 5.4, 5, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - Romans 13.11, undated (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - I Corin. 1.2 (2 copies), 1861-1862 (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - I Corin. 3.11, undated (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - I Corin. 6.19, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - I Corin. 9.24,25, undated (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - I Corin. 9.24,27, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 145)
    - I Corin. 11.23,25, undated (Box 15, Folder 145)